Inventory of the Jerdone Family Papers 1753-1890, 1771-1845
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Correspondence, 1753-1890. (Box 1-10)
  - Letters, 1800-1809., 155 items. (Box 4-5)
    - Letters, 1802., 28 items. (Box-folder 4:3)
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone [Sr.], Louisa [County, Virginia], 7 February 1802., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Refers to unsettled weather; refers to mortgage and how to finish business; explains how the Major has no liquid money to pay off mortgages; encourages to settle position on "discounts for negroes"; reports Helen Macaulay's intended marriage to son of James Southall, late of Williamsburg; other family news.
      - Turner Christian, Providence Forge, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 10 February 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Discusses shingles, some have arrived, some still on the way; encloses inspectors receipt for the h[og] h[ea]d of tob[acc]o; reports death of slave child "overlaid by its mother."
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone [Sr.], Louisa [County, Virginia], 28 February 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Reports drafts were all paid; refers to other accounts.
      - Geo[rge] Braikenridge, Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone [Sr.], [Louisa County, Virginia], 10 March 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Explains delay in goods; refers to events in Europe and to delay in obtaining a treaty; reports prices on goods and crops.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone [Sr.], Louisa [County, Virginia], 26 March 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Refers to weather and illness; reports on business with the Major and his mortgage; reports other accounts.
        Including invoice of payments by Turner Christian, 25 July 1800 and 20 May 1801. 1 page.
      - Geo[rge] Braikenridge, Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone, [Louisa County, Virginia], 6 May 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Hopes to receive letter soon; reports peace has finally been reached between France and England but doesn't expect to last long; worries as Britain has no allies.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone [Sr.], Louisa [County, Virginia], 7 May 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Refers to "the Alarm" which keeps Jerdone at home [alarm of Black revolt?]; reports on status of Major DuVal's account.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone [Sr.], Louisa [County, Virginia], 19 May 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Believes good reason to expect "an [Black uprising] attempt"; refers to Major DuVal's actions toward Gairdner; reports ratification of "Definitive Treaty" but has no details; wonders how it will affect business.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 21 June 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Discusses exchange of gold; reports business with Maj[or] DuVal almost completed; other news of health and weather; includes some accounts.
      - John Warden, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone [Sr.], Louisa County, [Virginia], 23 June 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Explains conditions of release for William DuVal from Jerdone.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone [Sr.], [Louisa County, Virginia], 25 June 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Explains status of DuVal affair and papers that have been drawn up; discusses other bonds; other family news.
      - Benj[amin] Bates, Jr., Hanover, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone [Sr.], Louisa [County, Virginia], 26 June 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Reports Sandy [Alexander] Macaulay's dissatisfaction at school and his desire to leave; explains Macaulay opposes the water used in the kitchen.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone [Sr.], Louisa [County, Virginia], 26 July 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Reports on DuVal affair; refers to difficulty in getting merchandise; inquires about butchers having come Jerdone's way; other family news.
      - Richm[on]d Lewis, n.p. to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 28 July 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:3)
        Requests payment from William Harris for medical services rendered.
        Including receipt from William Harris for medical services rendered by Dr. Richmond Lewis.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 21 August 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Describes Mr. Mitchell's illness and trip planned for his recovery; discusses various business dealings with Major DuVal, Turner Christian and in regard to Holt's lands.
      - Geo[rge] Braikenridge, Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone, [Louisa County, Virginia], 27 August 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Sorry to hear of another slave insurrect ion and hopes all is well; attributes trouble to effects of French Revolution in St. Domingo; requests any orders for goods be sent as soon as possible as regularity of ships for Virginia is non-existent; discusses crops and prices.
        Including invoice of goods sent to Francis Jerdone by Geo[rge] Braikenridge, 28 July 1798-26 September 1801. 1 page.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone [Sr.], Louisa [County, Virginia], 12 October 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Encloses "Holeman's" report and explains its significance; Major DuVal; reports on crops at the Forge; expresses desire for a visit.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone [Sr.], Louisa [County, Virginia], 23 November 1802., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Gives cost for Holeman's trip; reports "DuVal affair"; reports on Mr. Mitchell's trip to Norfolk.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone [Sr.], Louisa [County, Virginia], 10 December 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Congratulates on new son; extends wishes to Mrs. Jerdone for a speedy recovery; reports Mr. Mitchell's return.
      - Turner Christian, Providence Forge, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 13 December 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Reports on livestock, crops, and prices.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa, [Virginia], 15 December 1802., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Congratulates on increase in family; reports on tobacco.
    - Letters, 1803., 15 items. (Box-folder 4:4)
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 12 January 1803., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Discusses illness going around and some remedies; refers to repairs made in cooking utensils; other family news.
      - Turner Christian, Providence Forge, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 15 January 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Discusses cotton and hogs; enclosed accounts requested.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 25 February 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Refers to illness of Mrs. Mitchell and her children; congratulates on addition to family.
      - Joan Douglass, Jedburgh, [Scotland] to her cousin, Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, Virginia, 21 March 1803., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Informs that her mother died on the 13th of February; describes her illness; asks for news and letters of family.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 26 March 1803., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Discusses crop sales handled by Turner Christian; regrets that he cannot handle business of horses; discusses some tobacco business.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 1 April 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Reports that two h[ogs] h[ea]ds of tobacco have arrived at warehouse; reports fine weather has resulted in increase of tobacco being shipped.
      - Geo[rge] Braikenridge, Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone, in care of Mitchell V. Gardiner, Richmond, Virginia, 5 May 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Items sent; death of mother of Joan Douglass; possibility of war with France; bears invoice of Francis Jerdone.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 16 May 1803., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Reports has received two h[og] h[ea]ds of tobacco; also has received 27 gallons of oil and two kegs of "white lead"; cites current prices for these and tobacco.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 21 May 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Confusion continues as tobacco arrives; hopes oil arrived safely and will be sufficient; business "is dull" as the rumour of war affects country.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 8 June 1803., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Describes disastrous weather of hurricanes and hail; reports news from Turner Christian at Providence Forge; discusses tobacco and its inspection; fears for renewed conflict between France and Great Britain; gives current prices of wheat, corn and tobacco.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 11 June 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Refers to disastrous tornado [near Louisa County]; enclosed weights of two h[ogs] h[ea]ds [of tobacco]; asks him to accept four pineapples.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 25 July 1803., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Reports letter from the Commodore discussing learning navigation and naval tactics; refers to British attempt to acquire the French W[est] I[ndies]; reports no ships have arrived because of embargo; other family news.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 26 August 1803., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Received letter from Mr. Rob[er]t Johnson which he repeats; Mr. Christian requests some iron; comments on farmers opinions of crops; gives opinion of town people toward farmers.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 25 October 1803., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Discusses business; advises to let Turner Christian [overseer] sell the crops; reports weather and other aspects of business.
      - Turner Christian, Providence Forge, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 6 December 1803., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:4)
        Reports has sold old corn for 16 shillings per barrel; asks advice on sale of wheat; reports hogs will be ready by the 28th.
    - Letters, 1804., 14 items. (Box-folder 4:5)
      - Turner Christian, Providence Forge, [New Kent County, Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 3 January 1804., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Refers to boy to be sent to learn to be a blacksmith; reports on crops and goods sent.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], [January] 1804., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Refers to missing boy slave; reports "Anderson's Natt" won't take apprentices until they are 21 years old; advises to keep boy as laborer a few more years.
      - T[homas] Mitchell, n.p. to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 12 January 1804., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Has sent fourth of money; claims Britain watching for Bonaparte but no occurrences yet; hopes he will soon as Britain is well-prepared; requests to borrow some English newspapers sent by Mr. Braikenridge.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 2 February 1804., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Refers to letter lost with newspapers and intends to send papers separately; refers to boy slave's return; advises not to sell him but keep him as a "mechanic"; reports problems of slaves with [?] Hewlett; "I am sorry that Hewlett's conduct is so barbarous... It is no business of mine but several of the heads of negroe families at the forge complained of Hewlett to me. It may be worth your while to write Christian in order that no inhumanity may be used"; other business.
      - Geo[rge] Braikenridge, Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone, [Louisa County, Virginia], 7 February 1804., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Discusses business transactions through mail; discusses events and opinions in England toward the expected invasion of France; discusses weather, crops, and shipping; other family news.
      - Geo[rge] Weare Braikenridge, Bristol, [England] to his uncle, Francis Jerdone, [Louisa County, Virginia], 9 February 1804., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Describes the military forces prepared against France; dreads expense of this military endeavor; requests Jerdone to look for articles of Natural History; Includes list of things he collects.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, [Richmond, Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, Virginia, 5 March 1804., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Reports is getting over cough and describes some of the remedy; refers to the burning of Norfolk and estimates damage; reflects that this will affect prices.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 7 April 1804., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Reports on sale of crops and prices; reports on progress of stone steps; other family news.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 15 April 1804., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Reports his trip to England and explains he hopes to regain his health there.
      - Geo[rge] Gairdner, [Richmond, Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 18 April 1804., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Reports on goods purchased and sent; explains further details on trip to Great Britain.
      - Turner Christian, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 26 July 1804., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Reports on condition of crops and current prices; other family news.
      - John Warden, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 1 September 1804., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Williamsburg lawyer who helped prepare the Jerdone's suit against [William] Holt; describes his preparations of the suit; encloses the newspapers for damages.
      - Turner Christian, Providence Forge, [New Kent County, Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 3 December 1804., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Reports on crop condition and current prices; reports on hogs also.
      - W[illia]m Mitchell, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 8 December 1804., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:5)
        Reports [tobacco] has passed inspection; reports on Gairdner's health and on Sandy Mitchell's leg; refers to prices for tob[acc]o.
    - Letters, 1805., 21 items. (Box-folder 4:6)
      - T. Mitchell, n.p. to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 7 January 1805., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Sends payment to cover interest on bond; report on weather and crops.
      - Turner Christian, Pro[vidence] Forge, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 7 January 1805., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Discusses sale of wheat, transportation and harvest of cotton, corn crops and hogs; refers to Mr. William Mitchell.
      - Joan D[ouglass] Thomson, Jedburgh, [Scotland] to her cousin, Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, Virginia, 12 February 1805., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Thanks Jerdone for his consoling letter; refers to death of George Gairdner; announces her marriage on August 3, 1804 to Mr. Thomson; inquires of the Douglass'; invites Jerdone's nephew to visit her during his vacations at school; discusses the death of Mr. Waugh and his inheritance.
      - Ro[bert] Gairdner, Ed[inb]ur[oug]h, [Scotland] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 13 February 1805., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Reports death of George Gairdner; describes his perception of their friendship; explains connection made between Jerdone's cousin, Joan Douglass Thomson, and George; extends his help in whatever he can do.
      - T[homas] Mitchell, n.p. to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 24 February 1805., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Reports death of his brother on the 10th; describes conditions of will including freeing of his slaves; assures Jerdone accounts will be taken care of.
      - [George Braikenridge], Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone, [Louisa County, Virginia], 11 June 1805. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Explains that letter carried by Mr. Gairdner was delayed and this is why goods were delayed; includes list of goods shipped.
      - T. Mitchell, n.p. to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 1 July 1805., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Reports on due balance to Jerdone and events which will lead to payment; recommends Mr. Innes as agent to take care of his business.
      - T. Mitchell, n.p. to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia]. 7 July 1805., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Agrees 5% commission is outrageous and suggests a lower percent; reports on status of M[itchell] & G[airdner] House; requests Jerdone only draw $10,000 so as to preserve the existence of M & G.
      - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 23 July 1805., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Introduces himself and offers his services as an agent.
      - Geo[rge] Braikenridge, Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone, [Louisa County, Virginia], 28 July 1805., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Reports sent goods; sent copy of invoice to W[illia]m Cuthbert of Norfolk as he was agent for Mitchell & Gairdner; insured goods as have been reports of plundering by French Privateers; reports French left W. Indies before Lord Nelson arrived and now being pursued along coast of U.S.
      - Geo[rge] Braikenridge, Bristol, [England] to Francis Jerdone, [Louisa County, Virginia], 6 August 1805., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Refers to deaths of Mr. Gairdner and Mr. Mitchell; supposes Mitchell's executors will take care of goods; requests place to direct mail for Jerdone and Mr. Thompson.
      - Alex[ande]r Macaulay, Hampton, [Virginia] to his uncle, [Francis Jerdone], [Louisa County, Virginia], 10 September 1805., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Reports will not enter Navy; asks for recommendation of what profession he should pursue.
      - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 28 September 1805., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Discusses loan for Mr. Thompson; inquires if a personal security is sufficient or if he would prefer real estate; has had no shipment from Bristol.
      - T[homas] Mitchell, n.p. to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 7 November 1805., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Reports has received payment for tobacco from England; inquires whether Jerdone would like his payment in sterling or in currency; explains which is more convenient; advises he put money in Bank of England rather than Bank of Virginia because it pays interest.
      - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 26 November 1805., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Reports receipt of Major DuVal's mortgage; promises to finish matter soon or take legal steps.
      - W[illia]m Douglass, New Kent County, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 26 November 1805., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Requests Providence Forge estate be divided so that he may have his share inherited from his father; requests Jerdone go down in order to divide estate; feels this best and most economical way.
      - Turner Christian, Providence Forge, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 30 November 1805., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Reports on business; has 42 hogs ready by December 15th; wheat has been sold; corn not fully harvested yet.
      - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 3 December 1805., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Reports meetings with Major DuVal and Thomas Wilson; refers to unwillingness on Wilson's part to pay mortgage.
      - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 20 December 1805., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Reports has waited on business with DuVal sufficient time and now thinks it is time to go to court for payment; has sold wheat; gives list of goods sent by Abram.
      - Turner Christian, Providence Forge, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 21 December 1805., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Reports has sent 44 hogs and the accounts for 1804; relates had mentioned buying Mr. Douglass' share of the estate but Douglass is interested in buying another 1/4.
      - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 24 December 1805., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:6)
        Discusses preparations for lawsuit involving debts due Jerdone by Mitchell and Gairdner and Mr. DuVal; hopes to prevent suit from going into "Court of Chancery."
    - Letters, 1806., 13 items. (Box-folder 5:1)
      - T[homas] Mitchell, n.p. to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 15 January 1806., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:1)
        Sends interest on bond, suggests talking to bearer who has just returned from Mediterranean cruise.
      - John Warden, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 28 January 1806., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:1)
        Describes the conditions of payment of a mortgage debt; explains procedure used to settle conflict; gives conditions of proposals offered and results if go to court.
      - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 18 March 1806., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:1)
        Reports will receive detailed account of settlement with Major DuVal; does not feel this settlement is in Jerdone's best interest; debt has been transferred into hands of bank.
      - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 19 March 1806., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:1)
        Refers to letter sent explaining DuVal settlement.
      - Turner Christian, Providence Forge, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa County, [Virginia], 4 May 1806., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:1)
        Reports condition of wheat crops; has not sold Indian corn and expects low price; looks forward to Jerdone's visit to Providence Forge; other business matters.
      - Tho[mas] Mitchell, n.p. to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 13 May 1806., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:1)
        Discusses debt due by Mitchell & Gairdner; refers to dry weather; requests copy of accounts of 1804.
      - James Innes, Richmond, [Virginia] to Francis Jerdone, Louisa [County, Virginia], 12 June 1806., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:1)
        Reports offers of Mr. Brown to pay off whole debt of Mitchell and Gairdner; sorry to hear Mr. Christian will leave Jerdone's employ; relates mason has set of stone steps waiting to be picked up; requests instructions on those.